HARSH HARSH

• DETAILS •

San Diego United States 6282354291 singhharsh246@gmail.com

• LINKS •

Blog

Website

Github

<u>LinkedIn</u>

SKILLS

Docker

MySQL

Git

R

Python

SQL

Predictive Modeling

MongoDB

AWS Redshift

Data Science

Data Analytics

Experiment Design

Amplitude

PROFILE

Experienced Data Scientist with a passion for delivering valuable data through analytical functions and data retrieval methods. Committed to helping companies advance by helping them to develop strategic plans based on predictive modeling. Bringing forth a proven track record of analyzing complex data sets and serving as a strong advisor.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Data Scientist at Simpl, Inc., San Diego

July 2022 - Present

Series-B funded startup with over 1.5 million monthly active users, second largest BNPL player in India

- Instituted MIS automation, resulting in a weekly savings of 32 hours.
- Implemented rule-based filters based on user network connectivity, resulting in monthly savings of \$30,000 in defaulted money for Simpl.
- Led the productionization of **ML** models that leveraged user behavior data to catch fraudulent users, resulting in a **20**% reduction in experienced user delinquency.
- Successfully managed ad-hoc projects for CFO to meet business objectives.
- Actively collaborating with cross-functional teams to drive progress on a network analytics project focused on analyzing user defaulting behavior.

Product Analyst at Megashots Internet PVT LTD (getMega), Bengaluru

September 2019 — July 2021

One of the first 25 employees for a Series A funded "Pay to Play" gaming startup in a highly competitive market

- Consistently recognized as a top performer in bi-annual reviews.
- Achieved over a ten-fold increase in user engagement through Python-based personalized question difficulty algorithm to drive optimal engagement.
- Successfully reduced fraudulent users by **350**% through the creation and implementation of a detection and prediction model leveraging SQL and Python.
- Engineered a skill-based rating system utilizing SQL and Tableau to optimize matchmaking, driving a 500% increase in player engagement.
- Led multiple A/B tests, resulting in an incremental 25% increase in average user gameplay time.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Business Analytics, University of California, Davis, San Francisco August 2021 - June 2022

Nominated to **Beta Gamma Sigma** society as one of the top performers of 2022.

Highlighted Coursework: Advanced Statistics, Big Data, Machine Learning

Master of Science in Engineering (Mechanical), Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore September 2016 — April 2018

Highlighted Coursework: Computational Mechanics, Numerical Methods

Master and Bachelor of Technology, Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur, Kanpur $\operatorname{July} 2011 - \operatorname{June} 2016$

Highlighted Coursework: Linear Algebra, High-Performance Computing